<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>on-the-job on Hi, I&#39;m Xuan</title>
    <link>https://xuanli.me/tags/on-the-job/</link>
    <description>Recent content in on-the-job on Hi, I&#39;m Xuan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Xuan Li</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 08:40:57 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xuanli.me/tags/on-the-job/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Great Product Marketing: Airbnb’s 2021 Winter Release</title>
      <link>https://xuanli.me/posts/great-pmm-airbnb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 08:40:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xuanli.me/posts/great-pmm-airbnb/</guid>
      <description>When people say “Product Marketing”, Apple and Steve Jobs are often the first names that pop up. Apple shaped how modern technology products are marketed and Steve Jobs was the driving force. Their bi-annual Apple events where they announce the soon-to-be-released products and their annual developers conference (WWDC) continue to be the most watched product releases in the world.
It should come as no surprise then that Airbnb started releasing their updates in a similar way after hiring many of Apple’s marketing executives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go to Market Template for Consumer Products</title>
      <link>https://xuanli.me/posts/go-to-market-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:02:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xuanli.me/posts/go-to-market-template/</guid>
      <description>This template is designed to help consumer Product Marketers communicate their launch strategy to internal stakeholders. My former manager would always say: “this document should be a waterfall - each section should logically flow into the next.” For example, after defining the user pain points and key insight, the messaging framework should seem like it’s addressing those specific pain points. Having this logical progression makes it easier for teammates to follow along and understand the plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Product Marketing: 2021 Ford Bronco</title>
      <link>https://xuanli.me/posts/great-pmm-bronco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 09:40:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xuanli.me/posts/great-pmm-bronco/</guid>
      <description>This is the first in a series of Great Product Marketing posts where I dive into a company’s product marketing that I love. I find myself looking at the details of product launches, trying to piece together the Messaging Framework, and thinking about how it all came together.
The Ford Bronco relaunched to much fanfare and excitement in 2021. People had been cooped up inside due to the pandemic and wanted to be outside again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Positioning</title>
      <link>https://xuanli.me/posts/basics-of-positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 23:16:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xuanli.me/posts/basics-of-positioning/</guid>
      <description>Positioning is a word that is thrown around a lot and seems to morph into whatever vague definition the speaker wants it to mean. Sometimes it’s used to describe aspects of a marketing campaign and other times it’s used in competitive landscape discussions. I’ve thought about positioning a lot recently at my job and I wanted to put together a basic guide on positioning within the Tech world.
There are lots of definitions of positioning:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from a startup that translated into Big Tech</title>
      <link>https://xuanli.me/posts/lessons-from-a-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 11:04:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xuanli.me/posts/lessons-from-a-startup/</guid>
      <description>Our startup at an offsite where we graffitied a wall in SF
Before joining Lyft, I worked at a YC startup for several years in Business Development, Growth, and Product Marketing roles. I was employee #18 when I joined and we eventually grew to ~40 people before being acquired by Lyft in 2017. We built a good product with millions of app installs, but we never found a path to becoming a billion-dollar business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product Marketing Messaging Framework</title>
      <link>https://xuanli.me/posts/product-marketing-messaging-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 16:46:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xuanli.me/posts/product-marketing-messaging-framework/</guid>
      <description>Contents
 What is a Messaging Framework? The Get Framework Messaging Framework Let&amp;rsquo;s Do An Example  What is a Messaging Framework? The goal of the messaging framework is to clearly lay out the main message of campaign and why it is believable to the audience. In other words - what are you trying to tell the customer and why should they trust you? The messaging framework is most fundamental part of the Product Marketing brief and if done correctly, it will allow the rest of the elements of the brief to come together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
