<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career on Hi, I&#39;m Xuan</title>
    <link>https://xuanli.me/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career on Hi, I&#39;m Xuan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Xuan Li</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 11:04:27 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xuanli.me/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from a startup that translated into Big Tech</title>
      <link>https://xuanli.me/posts/lessons-from-a-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 11:04:27 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xuanli.me/posts/lessons-from-a-startup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://xuanli.me/images/lessons-startup/startup-offsite.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Our startup at an offsite where we graffitied a wall in SF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before joining Lyft, I worked at a YC startup for several years in Business Development, Growth, and Product Marketing roles. I was employee #18 when I joined and we eventually grew to ~40 people before being acquired by Lyft in 2017.  We built a good product with millions of app installs, but we never found a path to becoming a billion-dollar business. VC money is a bit of a double-edged sword in that sense - after raising $35M, it was billion dollar exit or bust for us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Marketing Roles</title>
      <link>https://xuanli.me/posts/tech-marketing-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 08:40:42 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xuanli.me/posts/tech-marketing-roles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my friends was looking to switch industries recently and mentioned that seeing all of the different marketing roles in Tech was pretty confusing for someone on the outside. The names of roles aren&amp;rsquo;t always consistent across companies and the job descriptions are generic enough that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell what type of work you&amp;rsquo;d be doing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to group the roles into larger buckets and give short descriptions of the work you&amp;rsquo;d do as a reference guide to those looking at marketing career pathways in Tech.  I hope this is useful for college grads or professionals looking to jump into Tech. A few things to note:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
